So how do you think you could describe these transformations numerically,
你会怎么用数字描述这些变换呢？
if you're say, programming some animations to make a video teaching the topic?
假设你要编写程序 制作动画视频来讲解这个知识点
What formula do you give the computer,
你会在计算机里输入什么公式呢？
so that if you give it the coordinates of a vector,
你需要输入这样的公式 在得到一个向量的坐标后
it can give you the coordinates of where that vector lands?
公式会给出向量移动后的坐标
It turns out that you only need to record where the two bases vectors,
其实你只需记录两个基向量
i hat and j hat,
î 和 ĵ
each land, and everything else will follow from that.
移动的落点 其它一切就水到渠成了
For example, consider the vector V with coordinates negative one, two.
比如 我们来看向量 V 其坐标为 [-1 , 2]
Meaning that it equals negative one times i hat,
也就相当于 -1 乘以 î 加
plus two times j hat.
2 乘以 ĵ 的和
If we play some transformation and follow where all three of these vectors go,
如果我们进行某种变换并观察这三个变量的落点
the property that grid lines remain parallel and
那么网格线保持平行
evenly spaced has a really important consequence.
等距分布这两点的重要性就体现出来了
The place where V lands, will be negative one times the vector where i hat landed,
V 变换后的落点等于 -1 乘以变换后的 î
plus two times the vector where j hat landed.
加 2 乘以变换后的 ĵ 的和
In other words, it started off as a certain linear combination of i hat and j hat,
换句话说 向量一开始是 î 和 ĵ 的某种线性组合
and it ends up as that same linear combination of where those two vectors landed.
变换后则为经过变换的向量 î 和 ĵ 的同一个线性组合
This means you can deduce where V must go based only on where i hat and j hat each land.
因此 只根据变换后 î 和 ĵ 各自的落点 你就可以推导出 V 会移动到哪里
This is why I like keeping a copy of the original grid in the background.
这就是我将原网格保留在背景里的原因了
For the transformations shown here,
我们来观察这个变换
we can read off that i hat lands on the coordinates one, negative two.
不难看出 Î 变换后落在坐标 [1 , -2] 处
And j hat lands on the x axis over at the coordinates three, zero.
ĵ 变换后则落在了 x 轴上 于是坐标为 [3 , 0]
This means that the vector represented by negative one i hat plus two times j hat,
这也就意味着 由 -1 乘 Î 加 2 乘 ĵ 表示的向量
ends up at negative one times the vector one negative two,
变换后等于 -1 乘向量 [1 , -2]
plus two times the vector three, zero.
加 2 乘向量 [3 , 0] 的和
Adding that all together you can deduce that it has to land on the vector five, two.
由此推断 向量 V 肯定会落在向量 [5 , 2] 处
This is a good point to pause and ponder because it's pretty important.
这个知识点特别重要 你最好停下来琢磨一会
Now, given that I'm actually showing you the full transformation,
因为我已经把整个变换过程做成动画了
you could have just looked to see that V has the coordinates five, two.
所以你很容易就可以找出 V 的坐标为 [5 , 2]
But the cool part here is that this gives us
但妙就妙在
a technique to deduce where any vectors land,
掌握了这个技巧 我们就能很方便地推导出任意向量的落点了
so long as we have a record of where i hat and j hat
只要我们知道  î 和 ĵ
each land without needing to watch the transformation itself.
变换后的位置即可 并不需要观察变换过程
Write the vector with more general coordinates x and y,
我们用更通用的坐标 x 和 y 来表示向量
and it will land on x times the vector where i hat lands,
变换后 向量就等于 x 乘向量 î 变换后的坐标 [1 , -2]
one negative two, plus y times the vector where j hat lands, three, zero.
加 y 乘向量 ĵ 变换后的坐标 [3 , 0] 的和
Carrying out that sum,
求和之后
you see that it lands at one x plus three y,
你就会发现 向量落在了坐标
negative two x plus zero y. I give you
[1x + 3y , -2x + 0y] 处 给你任意向量
any vector and you can tell me where that vector lands using this formula.
你都可以借助这条公式 告诉我向量的落点在哪里
What all of this is saying is that
这也就是说
a two dimensional linear transformation is completely described by just four numbers,
我们只需要四个数字 就能描述一个二维线性变换
the two coordinates for where i hat lands
这四个数字就是 î 变换后的两个坐标
and the two coordinates for where j hat lands.
和 ĵ 变换后的两个坐标
Isn't that cool? It's common to package these coordinates into
酷不酷？ 通常我们会把这些坐标打包放在一起
a two by two grid of numbers called a two by two matrix.
使之成为一个二乘二数字网格 即二乘二矩阵
Where you can interpret the columns as
矩阵的列
the two special vectors where i hat and j hat each land.
就是两个向量 î 和 ĵ 变换后的位置
If you're given the two by two matrix describing a linear transformation and
如果给你一个描述线性变换的二乘二矩阵
some specific vector and you want to know
和某个具体向量
where that linear transformation takes that vector,
求线性变换后的向量
you can take the coordinates of the vector,
你就可以分别将向量坐标
multiply them by the corresponding columns of the matrix,
与相应的矩阵列相乘
then add together what you get.
再进行相加 结果就出来了
This corresponds with the idea of adding the scaled versions of our new basis vectors.
这与将经过缩放的新基向量相加本质上是一致的